<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>University of Florida &#8211; Daniel&#039;s Adventures</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/tag/university-of-florida/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 03:50:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.3-beta1-46288</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Tips for upcoming exchange students to Florida</title>
		<link>http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/2019/09/22/tips-for-upcoming-exchange-students-to-florida/</link>
				<comments>http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/2019/09/22/tips-for-upcoming-exchange-students-to-florida/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 16:37:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[danielhonderd]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dutch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exchange student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[semester abroad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[University of Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USA]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://justgator.travel.blog/?p=108</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[In case someone might search for student exchange stories about UF, and stumble upon this site, I&#8217;ll prove a list of tips to help you. Always go for on-campus residence, it will be less luxurious than off-campus and you will probably share a room, meaning less privacy. But off-campus (international Weaver Hall for us, try [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In case someone might search for student exchange stories about UF, and stumble upon this site, I&#8217;ll prove a list of tips to help you.</p>



<ul><li>Always go for on-campus residence, it will be less luxurious than off-campus and you will probably share a room, meaning less privacy. But off-campus (international Weaver Hall for us, try to apply ASAP), means that you won&#8217;t be on a convenient location (having to take the bus etc.) And you won&#8217;t be with other Internationals (that generally have the same mentality of taking a less serious, and more outgoing approach for the semester.) </li><li>Sign up for the NAVIGATORS (the international association, not the Christian one), this will make it very easy to make a lot of American friends since you&#8217;ll be paired with an American. This is the reason you don&#8217;t need to be off-campus (where you&#8217;d meet other Americans)</li><li>On the first days you can get in the Weaver Hall (almost a week before the start of classes), you can find a donation center in the basement. This will have really useful kitchen utensils/clothing hangers/bedlinnen/lamps/mini-fridges(!!). The earlier you get here, the better the stuff that you can get here.</li><li>DONT take a meal plan. Unless you are extremely lazy at cooking and want to pay an overpriced meal plan that you&#8217;re gonna complain about after several weeks. You can still go to the dining hall and pay for your food separately if you really want to go. The options here are either fast food or extremely not appealing (so I&#8217;ve been told.)</li><li>Take transferwise as a debitcard, it has the same features (or even more) than most banks, and a low conversion rate. It uses Mastercard which means it&#8217;s a credit card from USA&#8217;s perspective. (The only thing you can&#8217;t pay with this is the ONE.UF bursar (for on-campus rent). </li><li>If you don&#8217;t need a lot of data, you can take RedPocket as a phone service plan, it has the cheapest plan with 3-4G available, you&#8217;ll have good wifi on campus and several pubs. (Having a different billing address than the shipment address is only possible if you contact them directly.)</li><li>Apply early for Gator Gears, it&#8217;s a bike rental service for 40 bucks a month, it&#8217;s super safe to bike on campus and if you&#8217;re careful/good biker you can take it to nearby supercenters as well. </li><li>Sign up for the six month Amazon Prime trial, as a student you are eligible for one. </li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/2019/09/22/tips-for-upcoming-exchange-students-to-florida/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Week 6: St. Augustine and froyo!</title>
		<link>http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/2019/09/22/week-6/</link>
				<comments>http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/2019/09/22/week-6/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 16:36:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[danielhonderd]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Weekly blogpost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dutch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exchange student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[semester abroad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[University of Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USA]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://justgator.travel.blog/?p=117</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[On Saturday, we went on a trip with the Navigators to St. Augustine, a very beautiful place as you will see in the pictures. Since it is/was a harbor, we also made use of the beach at the ocean (for me the first time since I&#8217;ve been in Florida). It was fun to meet other [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>On Saturday, we went on a trip with the Navigators to St. Augustine, a very beautiful place as you will see in the pictures. Since it is/was a harbor, we also made use of the beach at the ocean (for me the first time since I&#8217;ve been in Florida). It was fun to meet other people from the Navigators and we visited little shops in St. Augustine.</p>



<div class="alignnormal"><div id="metaslider-id-174" style="width: 100%;" class="ml-slider-3-14-0 metaslider metaslider-flex metaslider-174 ml-slider">
    <div id="metaslider_container_174">
        <div id="metaslider_174">
            <ul class="slides">
                <li style="display: block; width: 100%;" class="slide-175 ms-image"><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/f8f158fb-0ff5-4754-bfe3-ebc97adb8343-700x300.jpg" height="300" width="700" alt="" class="slider-174 slide-175" title="f8f158fb-0ff5-4754-bfe3-ebc97adb8343" /></li>
                <li style="display: none; width: 100%;" class="slide-176 ms-image"><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/img_1183-2-2560-700x300.jpg" height="300" width="700" alt="" class="slider-174 slide-176" title="img_1183-2" /><div class="caption-wrap"><div class="caption">At the corner of Castillo de San Marcos</div></div></li>
                <li style="display: none; width: 100%;" class="slide-177 ms-image"><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/img_1206-2560-700x300.jpg" height="300" width="700" alt="" class="slider-174 slide-177" title="img_1206" /><div class="caption-wrap"><div class="caption">In downtown St. Augustine</div></div></li>
            </ul>
        </div>
        
    </div>
</div></div>



<p><em>Fun facts</em></p>



<ul><li>Amount of guys I&#8217;ve seen with a tank-top: 5 per week en moyenne (I expected this to be a lot higher) </li><li>Amount of people that have complimented my Puma shoes: 9 so far</li><li>Amount of times I had to resort to Pepsi because Coca-Cola is almost never served at bars/campus <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f625.png" alt="😥" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> : 19</li><li>Amount of times my semi-fake-mentor Kristen has quoted &#8220;The Office&#8221;: too many to count  <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f605.png" alt="😅" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f605.png" alt="😅" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></li></ul>



<p>Another thing I love about UF, how lively everything is at night (since it is such a nice climate at night still). Wednesday we were asked by a tattooed guy with a hat if we wanted to do magic tricks with cards. The first trick I saw, but the rest of them really left me flabbergasted&#8230; </p>



<p>For Engineering Innovation, I had to come up with a need statement, for something that could be improved in society. For this I chose the fact that too many dogs are being bred instead of adopted from shelters. However, this meant that I had to put up questionnaires and interview people about this matter, I have to do something for which I hated other people in the past.. </p>



<p>Finally, I got to try something that I really always wanted to do since I&#8217;d seen it on the amazing show: &#8220;The Good Life&#8221; (here they interpreted heaven as a place that also has a  FROYO(!!) on every corner. Really, it&#8217;s amazing). For the first time in my life I tried frozen yoghurt, and it was setup in a such a way that you can choose your own flavors.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/snapchat-986469001-1.jpg?w=702" alt="" class="wp-image-132" width="287" height="419" srcset="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/snapchat-986469001-1.jpg 1440w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/snapchat-986469001-1-206x300.jpg 206w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/snapchat-986469001-1-702x1024.jpg 702w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/snapchat-986469001-1-768x1121.jpg 768w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/snapchat-986469001-1-1052x1536.jpg 1052w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/snapchat-986469001-1-1403x2048.jpg 1403w" sizes="(max-width: 287px) 100vw, 287px" /><figcaption>Frozen yoghurt at Menchie&#8217;s</figcaption></figure></div>



<p>On Friday we first went to GatorNights (if you go to almost all of them, you&#8217;ll get a prize). The highlight of this night was the Oxygen bar, something which apparently was also in the Netherlands. However, just as with froyo and goat yoga, I didn&#8217;t know we had this in my own country. The oxygen bar was a sketchy experience and a bit of a let down, but fun nonetheless. Talking about goat yoga, I might sign up for a class since they offer it at campus as well (as long as the goats decide not to shit on me, that is.)</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/mvimg_20190920_210003.jpg?w=768" alt="" class="wp-image-133" width="249" height="332"/><figcaption>Oxybar outside of Reitz on GatorNights</figcaption></figure></div>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/2019/09/22/week-6/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Week 5: Football game at UF</title>
		<link>http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/2019/09/15/week-5-football-game-at-uf/</link>
				<comments>http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/2019/09/15/week-5-football-game-at-uf/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 04:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[danielhonderd]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Weekly blogpost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dutch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exchange student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[semester abroad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[University of Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USA]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://justgator.travel.blog/?p=100</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s Saturday, and it&#8217;s the day of the first football game at campus. It&#8217;s the Gators against UT Martin. What to do on this day? First I will need to buy an orange shirt that will combine well with the blue bandana that my mentor gave me for the game. I already have an orange [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>It&#8217;s Saturday, and it&#8217;s the day of the first football game at campus. It&#8217;s the Gators against UT Martin. What to do on this day? First I will need to buy an orange shirt that will combine well with the blue bandana that my mentor gave me for the game. I already have an orange shirt, with UF &#8217;23 however, which essentially screams &#8216;Freshman&#8217;, so that&#8217;s not an option. So I went to the thrift shop, and bought this beautiful shirt with &#8220;I-L-L   I-N-I&#8221; on it, it was either this or the blood donor shirt so the decision was easy. After thrift-shopping, I joined my friends at the tailgating of the surf club. Which was a bit too fun, because I found myself hurrying towards Weaver to meet with a friend to get to the game in time. Something which apparently was not meant to be, since I had to login, already being in the application, to get the QR code. The correct password was not in my key-library and none of my own passwords worked, so I did a hail mary with resetting the password and hoping for a quick e-mail. This resulted in us being 6 minutes late for the game, which was not a big problem at all looking back. The game was fun, even though only 1 hour of the 3.15 hours was filled with the actual game. A lot of nice chants I could sing along (although they said gator bait at some point, which I really understood as Gatorade, confusing me a bit). </p>



<div class="alignnormal"><div id="metaslider-id-170" style="width: 100%;" class="ml-slider-3-14-0 metaslider metaslider-flex metaslider-170 ml-slider">
    <div id="metaslider_container_170">
        <div id="metaslider_170">
            <ul class="slides">
                <li style="display: block; width: 100%;" class="slide-171 ms-image"><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/img_1158-700x300.jpg" height="300" width="700" alt="" class="slider-170 slide-171" title="img_1158" /></li>
                <li style="display: none; width: 100%;" class="slide-172 ms-image"><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/img_1160-2560-700x300.jpg" height="300" width="700" alt="" class="slider-170 slide-172" title="img_1160" /></li>
                <li style="display: none; width: 100%;" class="slide-173 ms-image"><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/schocked-700x300.png" height="300" width="700" alt="" class="slider-170 slide-173" title="schocked" /><div class="caption-wrap"><div class="caption">If you look closely you can find me in the background</div></div></li>
            </ul>
        </div>
        
    </div>
</div></div>



<p>September the 8th, a special day for me, finally turning 21 in the USA. This day I had a pita gyros from the local Greek, which made me very happy. And don&#8217;t tell this to my parents, but I bought rum and vodka to celebrate with shots/mixed drinks with friends that evening. Gina gave me special color changing bike lights (for the spokes) as a present, a very cool gift!</p>



<p>On Wednesday, Gina decided to join Dennis, Kristen (my fake mentor) and me to the Grogs. A club that has free drinks and you only have to pay 5/3 dollars depending on you being 21+ or not. A very special night because Gina turns 20 at midnight!</p>



<h3><em>A story about my fake mentor&#8230;</em></h3>



<p><em>Before I actually was assigned to a mentor with the Navigators, it had been a couple of days since I applied and a lot of friends already were coupled with mentors. So at the Young Life BBQ event (a Christian organization that does extra non-religious activities), Dennis and I met Kristen. Kristen is a Young Life member who also really wanted to be in the Navigators, but thought she was too late to apply. Since we hadn&#8217;t heard anything from the Navigators we just created our own &#8220;fake&#8221; navigators mentor/mentees group. Later on, Dennis got paired with Sydney, and I with Gina. We asked our mentors if we could merge our two groups into one and apparently they already were best friends, what a coincidence! After this, we asked them to add Kristen as well, and with her and Gina talking in the: &#8220;The More the Merrier&#8221; group, they found out they were talking to someone they already knew, while walking out a meeting together of a club they are both in. That&#8217;s how, strangely, we all were connected somehow!</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/2019/09/15/week-5-football-game-at-uf/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Week 4: Survival</title>
		<link>http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/2019/09/07/week-4/</link>
				<comments>http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/2019/09/07/week-4/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 14:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[danielhonderd]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Weekly blogpost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dutch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exchange student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[semester abroad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[University of Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USA]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://justgator.travel.blog/?p=81</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Surviving at UF is no easy task. For groceries, I&#8217;ve tried going to Aldi by bus, which takes very long. I also tried going to the same Aldi by bike, which is perfectly doable, except for the way back&#8230; All food turns brown really quickly because of the humidity (bananas turn from green to brown [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Surviving at UF is no easy task. For groceries, I&#8217;ve tried going to Aldi by bus, which takes very long. I also tried going to the same Aldi by bike, which is perfectly doable, except for the way back&#8230; All food turns brown really quickly because of the humidity (bananas turn from green to brown in 4 days).  At least shopping at Amazon has been made more easy, since there is a 6-month prime trial for students. The easiness of shopping at amazon is something I miss at Walmart/Target, these places are so big that even the employees have to use an app to find the right division where the products are.  For now I think my best bet is to go beg to people with cars to take me with them when they go grocery shopping.  <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f605.png" alt="😅" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><br>The biggest difference that I notice now, is the luxury of eating whatever, and whenever you want. Daily egg/midnight yoghurt is no problem. I&#8217;ve also noticed that I have more time on my hands, since the academic level here is somewhat lower than I&#8217;m used to at TUDelft.  </p>



<p>It&#8217;s the fourth week, and I haven&#8217;t found a single alligator. Even though everyone tells me they are everywhere. At least I have taken revenge on this matter, by eating an alligator tail (!!!) burrito at Boca Fiesta, downtown. It tastes like sea chicken. I also tried the Boba Mango milk tea, at Bento, an Americanized Asiatic restaurant. Which had gummy-like &#8220;fish eggs&#8221;, as a friend put it.</p>



<p>Dayglow Paint Party!! We decided to go since it is free entrance (in heart and kidneys I stay Dutch) and because it sounded promising. And it was! The only worry I had was that it would not be easily washable, so I brought my most expendable clothes and hoped for the best (it turned out to be washable of course). </p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery columns-2 is-cropped"><ul class="blocks-gallery-grid"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/70188852_10157510353387618_8340433336115658752_o.jpg?w=1024" data-id="89" class="wp-image-89" srcset="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/70188852_10157510353387618_8340433336115658752_o.jpg 1944w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/70188852_10157510353387618_8340433336115658752_o-300x200.jpg 300w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/70188852_10157510353387618_8340433336115658752_o-1024x683.jpg 1024w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/70188852_10157510353387618_8340433336115658752_o-768x512.jpg 768w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/70188852_10157510353387618_8340433336115658752_o-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/70188852_10157510353387618_8340433336115658752_o-1568x1045.jpg 1568w" sizes="(max-width: 1944px) 100vw, 1944px" /></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/69656209_10157510451132618_8346866363901411328_o.jpg?w=828" data-id="88" class="wp-image-88" srcset="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/69656209_10157510451132618_8346866363901411328_o.jpg 828w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/69656209_10157510451132618_8346866363901411328_o-300x171.jpg 300w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/69656209_10157510451132618_8346866363901411328_o-768x439.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 828px) 100vw, 828px" /></figure></li></ul></figure>



<p>Tuesday, all classes are canceled because of the hurricane Dorian, as well as the next day. Little did we know that Dorian decided to alter its course and not bother us at all. However, a hurricane goes hand in hand with a hurricane party of course! This party was not cancelled naturally. At my Weaver Hall, on the first floor, a party was organized with different drinking games (BYOB for legal reasons). And here I met the first American with the claim of having Dutch roots, who actually could speak Dutch as well. It is common to hear Americans talking about also being of another nationality but not being able to speak a word in that language. </p>



<p>On Thursday, I had the luxury of being able to hitchhike with a friend to the Aldi, this friend couldn&#8217;t stop making fun of the fact that I actually was willing to buy meat etc. at the Aldi, making claims as &#8220;are you actually gonna eat that??&#8221; or &#8220;Ohh that&#8217;s gross!&#8221;. She, and some other random person at the Aldi, recommended me to go to the Publix supermarket after, so we did. Where I also got to try a Pub Sub. Being back at 7.15PM, we tried to get free shirts before the volleyball game of UF-Stanford. Unsuccessfully, since they came 4 shirts short for us to obtain one. It is a nice feature that all games (except for football, for which I got the season ticket), are free for students at UF.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/a2b0d46a-a037-4a85-8c2e-ec7b92ecb9c4.jpg?w=1024" alt="" class="wp-image-93" width="475" height="395" srcset="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/a2b0d46a-a037-4a85-8c2e-ec7b92ecb9c4.jpg 1587w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/a2b0d46a-a037-4a85-8c2e-ec7b92ecb9c4-300x250.jpg 300w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/a2b0d46a-a037-4a85-8c2e-ec7b92ecb9c4-1024x853.jpg 1024w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/a2b0d46a-a037-4a85-8c2e-ec7b92ecb9c4-768x640.jpg 768w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/a2b0d46a-a037-4a85-8c2e-ec7b92ecb9c4-1536x1280.jpg 1536w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/a2b0d46a-a037-4a85-8c2e-ec7b92ecb9c4-1568x1306.jpg 1568w" sizes="(max-width: 475px) 100vw, 475px" /><figcaption>UF vs Stanford volleyball game</figcaption></figure>



<p>It&#8217;s Friday, which means it&#8217;s time for: Gatornights! This day we decided to stand early in the line (more than an hour before it starts) to get a stuffed gator. After standing in several lines we finally got one! Well, half of us did. On this event they had also a mechanical gator for us to try out, this is the first time that I get why you have to sign a waiver before such an event since I arrived to the States (ouch!). </p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Mechanical Gator at Gatornights (7 sept &#039;19)" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C8nJ8yITrQs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/2019/09/07/week-4/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Week 3: Dorian knocking on the door?</title>
		<link>http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/2019/09/01/week-3/</link>
				<comments>http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/2019/09/01/week-3/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 08:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[danielhonderd]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Weekly blogpost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dutch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exchange student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[semester abroad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[University of Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USA]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://justgator.travel.blog/?p=66</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[On Sunday, an international food truck market was being held. Problem was, that the location would be at a walking distance of 45 minutes&#8230; The solution for me, and compromise for Gina (mentor), was going by bike. However, with Gina on the back of mine, something that was unimaginable for her. While everything went okay, [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>On Sunday, an international food truck market was being held. Problem was, that the location would be at a walking distance of 45 minutes&#8230; The solution for me, and compromise for Gina (mentor), was going by bike. However, with Gina on the back of mine, something that was unimaginable for her. While everything went okay, she feared for her life (sorry Gina!) and we got there safely. It was a good thing we decided to go, because I tried a delicious Puerto Rican empanada.</p>



<p>The next day, I got to try a &#8220;high quality Subway&#8221; as a friend put it; called the Firehouse Subs. It indeed was delicious and a bit out of town (25 minute walk). Then, just when we decided to go back, it started raining cats and dogs, unbelievably bad. Remember those 25 minutes? We also had to walk it back since the rain wouldn&#8217;t stop anytime soon. Also, the rain themed songs like &#8220;It&#8217;s raining men&#8221;, &#8220;Singin&#8217; in the rain&#8221; etc.  that the winkelcenter decided to put on, were really starting to annoy us ;). Of course, I had my nicest suede puma shoes on. So we thought: Fuck it, we&#8217;ll just put them in plastic bags (thanks to Target Copy) and walk barefoot to Weaver Hall (my dorm). </p>



<p>Sooo happy with the free food that is provided by different associations. Not yet really sure if it&#8217;s good for me though, on Tuesday we got free pancakes! Some of them with chocolate chips even. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/ed270ef5-cc4b-4408-922e-9cb4972ca999-1.jpg?w=1024" alt="" class="wp-image-74"/><figcaption>From left to right: Dennis, Gina and me! @YoungLife house with the pancakes</figcaption></figure>



<p>It&#8217;s time to prepare for: Dorian. A hurricane of probably cat 3 or 4 when it hits Florida. Sandbags are already handed out and people are reinforcing their doors. This is a strange thing to see and even stranger to hear about when you ask what it will be like. Water and electricity could fall out, which is why I&#8217;ll buy a baseball bat to defend my turf of the toilets (jk). I did do some grocery shopping, now I have enough water and glow sticks to survive this hurricane party. </p>



<p>On Friday we dared to go to the GatorNights, a weekly event with various activities. Besides waiting in line, we also got popcorn here to watch an improv group Shamilton, who had an amazing performance which included rap, dancing and a lot of humor. Also, we felt what it was like to move in a giant hamster wheel, while racing one another on a track with bumps. And of course we also did some board games here.</p>



<div class="alignnormal"><div id="metaslider-id-166" style="width: 100%;" class="ml-slider-3-14-0 metaslider metaslider-flex metaslider-166 ml-slider">
    <div id="metaslider_container_166">
        <div id="metaslider_166">
            <ul class="slides">
                <li style="display: block; width: 100%;" class="slide-167 ms-image"><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/1567144330614-846a03f9-1d80-4848-9a5b-2cbc733c1ebe-700x300.jpg" height="300" width="700" alt="" class="slider-166 slide-167" title="1567144330614-846a03f9-1d80-4848-9a5b-2cbc733c1ebe" /></li>
                <li style="display: none; width: 100%;" class="slide-168 ms-image"><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/img_20190830_212845-2560-700x300.jpg" height="300" width="700" alt="" class="slider-166 slide-168" title="img_20190830_212845" /><div class="caption-wrap"><div class="caption">The group Shamilton</div></div></li>
                <li style="display: none; width: 100%;" class="slide-169 ms-image"><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/img_20190830_225001-2560-700x300.jpg" height="300" width="700" alt="" class="slider-166 slide-169" title="img_20190830_225001" /><div class="caption-wrap"><div class="caption">Outside Reitz</div></div></li>
            </ul>
        </div>
        
    </div>
</div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/2019/09/01/week-3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Week 2: Frats and the Navigators</title>
		<link>http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/2019/08/25/week-2/</link>
				<comments>http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/2019/08/25/week-2/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 01:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[danielhonderd]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Weekly blogpost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dutch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exchange student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[semester abroad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[University of Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USA]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://justgator.travel.blog/?p=42</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Frat parties, a quick information guide about them can be found on Blue Mountain State on Netflix. I decided to attempt to get into one with my German floormember Leo. Our plan was simple, buy a six-pack of beer and use that as a bribe to get into the party. The six-pack became a 12-pack [&#8230;]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Frat parties, a quick information guide about them can be found on Blue Mountain State on Netflix. I decided to attempt to get into one with my German floormember Leo. Our plan was simple, buy a six-pack of beer and use that as a bribe to get into the party. The six-pack became a 12-pack and it was 7 dollars each. At the fraternity house Delta Epsilon we sneaked in with another group, and we met nice people there. It was fun and way more relaxed than I thought it would be, we were the only ones that brought something and it wasn&#8217;t even needed, we were told. The party turned out to be more of a chill session (30-35 people) and it wasn&#8217;t &#8220;<em>stroef</em>&#8221; at all. However, several people asked me what I did to become a frat, apparently the beard does it all&#8230; I also taught them how to play stresspong, also called rage-cage for the people to the east of Utrecht. So all in all it was a unique and very fun experience. </p>



<p>All fun and games is over, now the academics begin. It&#8217;s Tuesday, and there are 2 classes on my agenda, ancient Greek philosophy and Programming fundamentals 1 (programming Java 101). But before all this I had to pick up my rental bike, I almost had to promise to use the helmet for my safety, a promise which I of course would have to break. The bike is a bit worrisome, since it apparently has the worst (peddle) brakes in history, forcing me to brake 3 meters before I actually have to stop. The helmet idea actually makes sense now.  <br>I somehow managed to get late at my philosophy class (old habits never die), and was surprised about the amount of students (just 25) and the amount of papers I would have to write (both by hand and computer for no apparent reason). Java 101 did not turn out to be Java 101, it was a very confusing course with 650(!) students. Almost all of them freshmen and all of them very noisy/rude to the teacher. The teacher told us this was only required for the CSE Major and a course specialized in only Java should be taken if that was the goal out of this course. So I did. F*ck the disorganized class and their robbery of trying to get me to buy 50 dollar clickers. Which apparently is a device to answers in-class quizzes, to potentially get 10 points out of a thousand&#8230; </p>



<p>I joined the Navigators! Which, as it seems, is not a Christian organization at all, it&#8217;s solely purpose it to connect internationals with Americans and organize trips/events for them. I got paired up with Gina, a lovely and very social person, and I know for sure that we will have a fun time as a Navigator buddy group!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/image-3.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-50"/><figcaption>From left to right: Gina, Dennis, Sydney (mentor of Dennis), me! This was at Chipotle</figcaption></figure>



<p>The next couple of days I had to focus on which courses I wanted to have, since the UF has a drop/add week in which you can switch those. I ended up with Greek philosophy, Java (related to programming fundamentals but more focused on just Java), Engineering Entrepreneurship and Engineering Innovation.</p>



<p>On Wednesday, I went out with the &#8220;We&#8217;re so Fucking Kind&#8221; group to Grogs, where I ironically drank too much. I would ask for a coke zero at the bar and get a spiked one instead. It was a fun night. <br>Back in my dorm, I decided it was a good idea to do two things simultaneously: brushing my teeth and getting ready for bed. Which meant that I found myself a couple of seconds later outside my room, without keys (the doors lock automatically from the outside), and no roommate present. Luckily I could sleep (although I haven&#8217;t actually slept for a bit) at Christofer, a good friend of mine. After which I returned to my room at 8, to catch up my missed sleep, resulting in missing my first couple of classes.</p>



<p>Gina, as a good mentor she is, took me to several events (like Krishna, vegetarian food) and introduced me to many of her friends. I felt accepted and had a fun time at wherever she took me. Thank you Gina!</p>



<div class="alignnormal"><div id="metaslider-id-161" style="width: 100%;" class="ml-slider-3-14-0 metaslider metaslider-flex metaslider-161 ml-slider">
    <div id="metaslider_container_161">
        <div id="metaslider_161">
            <ul class="slides">
                <li style="display: block; width: 100%;" class="slide-163 ms-image"><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_7299-1-2560-700x300.jpg" height="300" width="700" alt="" class="slider-161 slide-163" title="img_7299-1" /><div class="caption-wrap"><div class="caption">In the French Fries before Reitz</div></div></li>
                <li style="display: none; width: 100%;" class="slide-164 ms-image"><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/1566671219982-4501b420-b1b1-4fb2-883d-5b006b5afd6f-700x300.jpg" height="300" width="700" alt="" class="slider-161 slide-164" title="1566671219982-4501b420-b1b1-4fb2-883d-5b006b5afd6f" /><div class="caption-wrap"><div class="caption">At GatorNights</div></div></li>
                <li style="display: none; width: 100%;" class="slide-165 ms-image"><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/1566672706589-f8abadfc-d9d0-4feb-b838-2d9abad1882f-1-700x300.jpg" height="300" width="700" alt="" class="slider-161 slide-165" title="1566672706589-f8abadfc-d9d0-4feb-b838-2d9abad1882f-1" /></li>
            </ul>
        </div>
        
    </div>
</div></div>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/2019/08/25/week-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Week 1: The arrival to the US of the A Paragraph</title>
		<link>http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/2019/08/18/example-post/</link>
				<comments>http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/2019/08/18/example-post/#comments</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 15:37:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[danielhonderd]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Weekly blogpost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dutch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exchange student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[semester abroad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[University of Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USA]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://justgatortravel.wordpress.com/?p=3</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[My experiences at UF as an exchange student of this week.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Travelling by plane was exhausting, made me a little bit grumpy, and even a bit stressed. Luckily I traveled with a Dutch friend from the same university. Apparently, I was tired enough to leave my rain jacket at the Orlando Airport. No biggy, since it doesn&#8217;t rain in Gainesville right? Arriving at the University of Florida, I mainly notice 2 things, the fact that there are actually bicycle roads, and the size of the campus; filled with a lot of brick buildings. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery columns-3 is-cropped"><ul class="blocks-gallery-grid"><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_185329-1-1024x768.jpg" alt="" data-id="30" data-full-url="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_185329-1-2560.jpg" data-link="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/img_20190814_185329-1/" class="wp-image-30" srcset="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_185329-1-1024x768.jpg 1024w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_185329-1-300x225.jpg 300w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_185329-1-768x576.jpg 768w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_185329-1-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_185329-1-2048x1536.jpg 2048w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_185329-1-1568x1176.jpg 1568w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_184706-768x1024.jpg" alt="" data-id="26" data-full-url="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_184706-2560.jpg" data-link="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/img_20190814_184706/" class="wp-image-26" srcset="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_184706-768x1024.jpg 768w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_184706-225x300.jpg 225w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_184706-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_184706-1536x2048.jpg 1536w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_184706-1568x2091.jpg 1568w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_184706-2560.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /></figure></li><li class="blocks-gallery-item"><figure><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_183718-1-2-1024x768.jpg" alt="" data-id="36" data-full-url="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_183718-1-2-2560.jpg" data-link="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/img_20190814_183718-1-2/" class="wp-image-36" srcset="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_183718-1-2-1024x768.jpg 1024w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_183718-1-2-300x225.jpg 300w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_183718-1-2-768x576.jpg 768w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_183718-1-2-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_183718-1-2-2048x1536.jpg 2048w, http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190814_183718-1-2-1568x1176.jpg 1568w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure></li></ul><figcaption class="blocks-gallery-caption">On UF campus</figcaption></figure>



<p>Somehow, I managed to lose my key fob for the building on my first day in Weaver Hall, the international student hall. This was unfortunate, but it did not affect my happiness, I finally was at UF, GO GATORS. I got an invitation from Dennis, the Dutch friend, to have dinner with his roommate off-campus, in other words: a 40-minute walk. Definitely worth it! After this, his kind roommate even offered me a ride back, after finding out I did that impossible 50 minute walk!</p>



<p>The next day, I found a real jungle in the middle of campus, time to find some alligators! This day my roommate also arrived, with almost 4 times the amount of luggage, he managed to put it just as (dis)organized as me. Apparently, the whole of Florida sleeps/lives in a cold environment by turning the AC on the highest setting. To sleep under a lot of blankets after, bit strange if you ask me\_(ツ)_/.</p>



<p>My intention for these couple of days before all classes start: try to absorb as much information about campus (what&#8217;s good etc.) and enjoy. The two associations most open to internacho&#8217;s are: BCM and Navigators, both christian associations. They organized parties, game nights, midnight munchies (pancakes).  I applied for Navigators, after making sure it was not a problem that I would not partake at the more religious events. They would pair me with a American mentor, so that should be fun. How nice would it be to join a frat? I am still doubting.</p>



<p>On Friday evening the RA&#8217;s (resident assistents of the building) organized a meetup with free sandwiches, if something makes me happy, it&#8217;s free food! After playing some board games there with the Internacho&#8217;s and not Internacho&#8217;s (every international gets paired up with an American), we went to a local pub on edge of campus; The Salty Dog. I was with a group of Internacho&#8217;s. There we found out that: We are Fucking Kind. </p>



<p>Just a couple of days left before classes start, I am quite certain I&#8217;ll have to switch some classes on the first week, it&#8217;s just a feeling. We got to see the Gator Stadium, quite huge! I will probably want to buy some tickets. In the evening, I got to see the American version of the Macarena, at a party hosted by Navigators (again, with free food). It was a group dancing on &#8220;Cha Cha Slide&#8221;, and it was very amusing to see. Back at weaver hall we got to talking about what I could do or see in Florida. It would be nice to go on a trip to the Bahamas, surf in Tampa, join a powerlifting association and go hiking/trips. What do you think I should really do?</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/img_20190817_122543.jpg" alt="This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is img_20190817_122543.jpg"/><figcaption> The Swamp football stadium </figcaption></figure>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.danielvanpaass.github.io/danielblog/2019/08/18/example-post/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
